miami-dadeclerk.com 2019-12-31

# Privacy and Security Notice

This policy applies to all official Miami-Dade County web sites and describe what information we collect, how we use that information and your options regarding information collections.

## Information We Collect

When you visit County web sites, we may collect some information from you. This information does not identify you personally and may include:

  * Your Internet protocol address
  * Date and time of visit
  * Referring links
  * Search terms
  * Links you click on
  * Your browser
  * Your operating system.

### Personal Information

If you choose to provide us with personal information – by filling out a form with your personal information and submitting it to us through the website – we use that information to respond to your message and to help us get you the information you have requested. We only share the information you give us with another government agency if your inquiry relates to that agency, or as otherwise required by law.

### Payment Information

County websites do not collect or store payment information. In instances where payments are processed, the County uses third-party service providers external to miamidade.gov to manage payments.

### Social Media

Our websites may include social media features, such as newsfeeds, that are hosted by a third parties, such as Facebook or Twitter. This policy does not apply to such features. Your interactions with social media features are governed by the privacy policy and other policies of the respective companies providing them.

## How We Use Information We Collect

We use the information we collect to help us make the site more useful to visitors -- to learn about the number of visitors to our site and the types of technology our visitors use, for example. We do not track or record information about individuals and their visits, except as described in this policy.

### Use of Personal Information

Any personal information collected, such as an email address submitted by you for the purposes of subscribing to a newsletter, is used to get you the information you have requested. We don’t share your information with other agencies or parties, except as required by law.

Navigational Information  
Information, such as the pages you visit or the links you click, helps us improve our websites and provide better service. The County does not use this information to identify you personally.

### Cookies and Beacons (Pixels)

Some information we gather about you is stored on “cookie,” a small file that is sent to and stored on your computer. Our website and other technologies employed as part of our web presence can read the information, such as preferences and visit history information, stored in this cookie for the purposes of providing you with a better web experience.

Some County sites and pages may also employ web beacons or pixels to help us gauge and serve effective content. Beacons, clear gifs, or pixels are small, invisible images, roughly the size of a pixel, that are embedded on our web pages that collect information about your visits. The information collected this way is not used to personally identify you.

### External Websites

Our web sites may link to many other governmental agencies. In some cases, we link to private organizations. Once you link to another site, you are subject to the privacy policy of that respective site.

## Site security

For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, this government computer system employs commercial software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. Except for authorized law enforcement investigations, no other attempts are made to identify individual users or their usage habits. Raw data logs are used for no other purposes and are scheduled for regular destruction in accordance with State guidelines for records management and retention. Unauthorized attempts to upload information or change information on this service are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act.

## How We Share Information We Collect

As a rule, the County does not disclose any personally identifiable information collected online except where you have given us permission, or where the information is requested to be disclosed and is public information under the State of Florida statutes or other applicable laws. Visitors to the site should be aware that Florida Statute 119 declares that it is the policy of this state that all state, county, and municipal records shall be open for personal inspection by any person, and thus information collected by the County resulting from the use of its websites may be subject to examination and inspection upon request, if such information is a public record and not otherwise protected from disclosure by statute.

Under Florida law, e-mail addresses are public records. If you do not want your e-mail address released in response to a public records request, do not send electronic mail to this entity. Instead, make contact by phone or in writing.

## Passwords

In certain instances, you will have the opportunity to receive or create a password to access or submit personal information. You should not divulge your password to anyone and the County will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or e-mail. When you are finished with those applications that are password protected, you should logout, where applicable, and exit the page.

## Your Options/Opting Out

You may decline participation in any activity that asks for information (i.e., surveys or emails). Your choice to not participate will have no effect on your ability to access information on the County's web sites.

You can adjust your browser settings to limit or block cookies. For instructions:

Note that some applications and pages need cookies to store history and preference information and that disabling cookies may affect the performance of these pages and applications.

The website has links to many other governmental agencies. In some cases we link to private organizations. Once you link to another site, you are subject to the privacy policy of the new site.
